Some say he's dead...some say he never will be.
Jeremiah Johnson is a adventure, western, drama film directed by Sydney Pollack.
A mountain man who wishes to live the life of a hermit becomes the unwilling object of a long vendetta by
Indians when he proves to be the match of their warriors in one-on-one combat on the early frontier.
Jeremiah Johnson, played by Robert Redford.
Bear Claw, played by Will Geer.
Swan, played by Delle Bolton.
Caleb, played by Josh Albee.
Paints His Shirt Red, played by Joaquín Martínez.
Crazy Woman, played by Allyn Ann McLerie.
Jeremiah Johnson is a 1972 American Western film directed by Sydney Pollack and starring
Robert Redford as the title character and Will Geer as "Bear Claw" Chris Lapp.
It is based partly on the life of the legendary mountain man John Jeremiah Johnson, recounted in Raymond Thorp and Robert
Bunker's book Crow Killer: The Saga of Liver-Eating Johnson and Vardis Fisher's 1965 novel Mountain Man.
The script was written by John Milius and Edward Anhalt; the film was shot at
various locations in Redford's adopted home state of Utah.
It was entered into the 1972 Cannes Film Festival on May 7, 1972, and
was later released on December 21, 1972, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews from critics, and was a box-office success, earning $44.7 million
against a budget of $3.1 million, making it the 5th highest-grossing film of 1972.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, loss of
loved one, rocky mountains, survival, snow.
The tone is emotional.